<?xml version="1.0" encoding='ISO-8859-1'?>
<section id = "switch">
    <title>Bootloader-specific function calling mechanism</title>
    <para>
Each bootloader-specific module must provide function, which returns map describing the functions provided by the bootloader-specific module.
Details about return value are available in Bootloader-specific module description section.
    </para>
    <para>
Since future versions of YCP interpreter may need to parse and check all (possibly) used module and include files, all files of all bootloaders
must be present (which forbids architecture-dependent conditional presence of bootloader-related files in .spec file).
    </para>
    <para>
The <computeroutput>getFunctions</computeroutput> function is the only point, where all bootloader must be listed. It's task is to choose
depending on parameter specifying bootloader which set of bootloader-specific functions should be used. In the body of this functions, there
is stored map from bootloader identifiers to term, which after evaluation returns the set of bootloader-specific functions.
From this map term to evaluate is choosen and evaluated, and this map is a return value of this function.
    </para>
    <para>
Each function, which should be able to be called without checking of bootloader, has s shortcut (usually called like eg.
<computeroutput>blRead</computeroutput> for <computeroutput>Read</computeroutput> function). This function gets list of functions for currently
used bootloader, chooses term appropriate to the concrete function, depending on concrete function and it's parameters adds some parameters if needed,
and evaluates the term. If some value should be returned (depending on concrete function), returns result of the evaluation of the term.
If there is no entry in map representing appropriate bootloader-specific function, then generic version of the function (locater in the BootCommon module)
is called.
    </para>
    <para>
There is (at least currently) no automatical way to generate these functions, each of them must be written manually.
    </para>
</section>
